until now we've been using reactive references to declare all of our reactive properties
到目前为止，我们一直在使用响应式引用来声明我们所有的响应式属性
however the composition syntax comes with another equally valid way declare reactive properties
然而，复合API语法有另一个同样有效的方法去响应式的声明一些属性
which I want to show you now
我现在就给你秀一下
use it instead of reactive references first we need to import  be ractive
使用reactive代替reactive reference 首先我们要先引入reactive
I will create an event constant and called the reactive function
创建一个event常量，称为响应式函数
it returns a reactive object
它返回一个响应式对象
send in an object with each of the properties that we want to be reactive
派发一个对象，其中包含我们想要的每个属性
notice here it even contains our computed property
注意这里它甚至包含了我们的计算属性
this might feel a little more familiar since we're used to declaring
我们可能有点熟悉,因为我们过去常常用option API 的data来声明我们的响应式对象
reactive object using our data option
we are doing here is taking a reactive references
我们在这里做的是响应式而不是
instead declaring them in an object
在对象里面声明它们
you should notice that inside of her computed property
你应该能发现在computed属性
I no longer have to use dot value
不再使用.value 了
since our object is taking care of reactivity
因为我们考虑的是响应式
Then we'll declare a method
然后我们会声明一个方法
again we don't have to use dot value
我们也不会使用.value
we can just say event dot capacity plus plus
我们可以写event.capacity++
and lastly notice I can send the entire event object
最后请注意，我可以派发整个事件对象
into the template
返回到模板中
Both of these are completely valid syntaxes
这两种语法完全都是有效的
It's up to you which one you use
取决你想选择哪一种
our template is going to look a little different
我们的模板看起来会有点不同
here we have to specify event dot event dot event dot
这里我们必须指定event.dot
to access the properties on this reactive object
去访问这个对象上的属性
I saw this code I kinda of didn't like it
当我看到这段代码的时候我不太喜欢这样
like, I wanted to be able to destructure
比如说,我想破坏结构
that event object into pieces so that
这个event对象变成了一段一段的
in my template I didn't have to say event dot
在我的模板中, 我不得不使用event.dot
I really wondered if I could destruction this event object so my template
我真的很想知道我是否可以破坏这个事件对象的结构，这样我的template
didn't have to have a event on
就没有点了
now that i've changed my template it wouldn't currently work
现在我已经改变了我的template，它目前不起作用
To make this work I would have to change how I'm returning the event
为了让这个起作用,我不得不返回这个事件
my first guess
我的第一个猜测
it's just to use dot dot dot however that didn't work
使用...去结构 但是没用
second guess was simply to list out each of the properties
第二个猜测是简单地列出每个属性
but also error out
但是也错了
problem here is that splitting apart the event object is going to remove its reactivity
问题是拆分event会使响应式消失
it's not going to work
这是行不通的
The solution here is to take
解决方案是
to take our reactive object split each object up into its own reactive references
把我们的响应式对象拆分成一个一个的reactive ref
Luckily,Vue3.0 come with a function called toRef
幸运的是,vue3.0附带了一个函数叫toRef
So I'll import it
我会引入
and then if I send event into this function
如果我把事件发送到这个函数
it's going to convert my reactive object
它会改变我的响应式对象
each property being a reactive reference
每个属性都是响应式引用
that points to the property on the original object
指向原始对象的属性
I do a mention though but if I didn't need to expose increase capacity
不过我还是想提一下如果我不需要让capacity++
my template
我的模板
I could instead simply write
我可以直接写
toRefs event
return toRefs(event)
And I wouldn't need to destructure it
我不需要去解构event
simply returning a plain object
直接return一个对象
which is what our setup function
这就是我们的setup功能
is expected to return
被return回来